My name is Greed.
我的名字叫葛利德
But…
不过啊
it seems you already know who I am.
你们看起来好像早就认识我了
Greed,
葛利德
shut down the labyrinth immediately and surrender.
马上给我关闭迷宫 并且乖乖投降
If you do, I'll spare you.
这样我就饶你一条小命
Oh, my… And why should I?
哎呀 我为什么要听你的话？
We've wiped out all the monsters
你派到镇上的魔物全都被我们消灭了
You should be aware of our strengths.
你也看到我们的战力了吧？
Is that so?
是这样吗？
He sent out that many monsters again!
居然又派了那么多魔物
Rud, calm down!
路德 你冷静点
That's right. I can't let him get to me.
没错 我要冷静一点
It's regrettable.
很遗憾
Merely relying on those monsters
光靠你派出去的那些战力
won't be enough to defeat Avancia.
是不可能击溃阿凡锡亚的
Is that really the case?
真的是这样吗？
I can continuously summon monsters with nearly unlimited points, you know?
我可是能用近乎无限的点数 不断召唤魔物喔
It's only a matter of time…
攻下那里只是时间的问题罢了
On another note,
话说回来
there's something I've been curious about.
有件事让我一直很在意
Those two over there
那边的两个人
are Homunculi, right?
是人造人吧？
Miss Luna is also a Homunculus?
露娜小姐也是人造人？
What are you talking about…?
你在说什么啊？
Yes.
没错
And?
但是那又如何？
Nothing.
没什么
I'm just a little moved, that's all.
我只是有点感动罢了
After all, in my past research,
毕竟在我过去的研究中 从没看过像你这样
I've never seen Homunculi grow as remarkably as you!
成长得这么出色的人造人
I never expected that living outside could have such an impact on Homunculi!
没想到在外面生活 居然能带给人造人这种影响
How about it?
怎么样？
Won't you come back to me?
想不想回到我身边啊？
Sir Rud is my one and only master!
我的主人只有路德大人一个人！
Luna. Rud.
露娜、路德
Why didn't you tell us?
你们为什么瞒着我们？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I'm sorry that I kept it from you--
一直瞒着你们真的很抱…
Good grief.
真是的
You better explain yourself when we get back.
之后要好好跟我们说明喔
Luna!
露娜
Yes!
好的！
My, my…
真是的
In that case…
那么…
I might as well take everything by force.
我干脆把一切都夺过来好了
Although I'm not quite fond of this form of mine very much.
虽然我不是很喜欢这副模样的自己
Such a heavy attack!
好沉重的攻击
But as long as I reinforce my whole body with mana…
不过只要用魔力强化全身的话…
Samimina, dodge!
萨米弥娜 快退下！
Are you all right?
你还好吗？
I'm fine.
还好
More importantly,
话说回来
did you block that damage with your shield force?
你刚才是帮我挡下了护盾的损伤吗？
-Yes. -You don't have to do that.
-没错 -你不必这么做
My life is meant
我这条命是用来拯救所有人造人的
You can use me as a disposable weapon!
你可以把我当作 用完就丢的武器使用！
So whether you live or die doesn't matter as long as we defeat Greed?
只要能打倒葛利德 你是生是死都无所谓吗？
Yes.
是的
Then…
好吧
do not participate in this battle.
那你不准参加这场战斗
Because I don't want to lose anyone.
因为我不希望有人因此牺牲
I am a Homunculus. I don't have a life to begin with.
我是人造人
Greed only sees you as a tool to use.
葛利德只把你们当道具使用
Are you trying to make me treat you
你这样是想让我变成 你们最讨厌的那种人吗？
If not, then don't sacrifice yourself in battle,
不是的话
do you understand?
知道吗？
I'm surprised you guys still have the leisure to chat.
你们还有闲情逸致在这里聊天
-Magic Shield!
-魔法防护罩！
So you've got tricks up your sleeves.
小伎俩还挺多的嘛
Is that a skill?
这是技能吗？
How annoying.
真讨人厌啊
What?
什么？
I nullified your magic.
我把你的魔法无效化了
How dare you!
好大的胆子
You rascals! How dare you do this to me!
混账 你们竟敢这样对我！
L-Let go of me! Let go of me!
放开我 快放开我！
Could it be that these cuffs are…
难道这手铐是…
Curses!
可恶
Take this!
看招！
Life Burst!
生命爆发！
Sir Hero…
勇者大人
Don't let your guard down!
别松懈！
Y-Yes!
好的
You guys did well.
你们真的很厉害
So have some confidence in yourselves!
所以给我有自信一点
-Yes.
-是
Amazing!
好厉害
Miss Amon, please join the battle as well.
亚蒙小姐 请你也一起来战斗吧
But I'm tired.
但我已经累了
I do not fancy a man that is annoying.
人家可不喜欢太烦人的家伙
Lady Manicia
玛妮西娅大人说
prepared these super sweet doughnuts for the hardworking Miss Amon.
这个超甜的甜甜圈 是要做给努力战斗的亚蒙小姐的
Shall I tell her not to bother with them
要我跟她说你没在战斗
W-What?
什么？
Why didn't you say so earlier?
你倒是早点说啊
I never said I wasn't going to fight!
我可没说自己不战斗喔
My woeful kin,
可怜的眷属们啊
return to the darkness!
回归黑暗吧
Chat Magic Balnoir!
恰特魔法巴尔努瓦！
Run!
快逃！
Well then, let's take Greed back to the town with us.
那我们也带着葛利德回镇上吧
What's this?
这是…
Do Demon Lords have such magic stones in their chests?
魔王的胸口有这种魔石吗？
No, could it be…
不对 难道说…
What's going on?
怎么回事？
This magic…
这股魔力
It's nothing like we've ever been up against.
强到无法和过去的对手相提并论
Are you the real one?
你就是本尊吗？
I created him based on my memories and abilities,
他是我按照自己的 记忆和能力做出来的
so I'd say that Homunculus is as good as the real one.
所以那个人造人姑且也算本尊喔
Though its combat abilities leave much to be desired.
不过战斗力好像做得太弱了
My name is Greed.
我的名字叫葛利德
A pleasure to make…
初次见面
I believe we can skip the formalities.
这种客套话应该就免了吧
We'll soon bid each other farewell anyway.
反正我们很快就要说再见了
Rud!
路德！
I'm fine!
我没事！
With a lift of his finger, he can conjure up such a powerful attack!
他只是轻轻动一下
I must use my mana to make myself stronger or else…
必须用魔力更加强化自己 否则无法打败他
Rud!
路德！
No point in using the move we used for Amon…
看来无法用攻击亚蒙的那招对付他
-Skill: Fusion!
-技能 融合
Don't worry. Keep attacking like this.
别担心 就这样继续攻击
Prepare yourself!
觉悟吧！
Miss Samimina!
萨米弥娜小姐！
Thank you!
谢谢你
Everyone, regroup.
所有人重整态势
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Master!
主人！
That took a great deal off my shield force.
护盾被消耗掉了很多
I'll distract him.
我来引开他的注意
Please restore Rud's shield force.
麻烦你帮路德回复护盾
Got it.
知道了
Even as Lilialy,
即便是莉莉亚莉
they can only defend against Greed.
对上葛利德也只能一个劲地防守啊
We'll have to seize the opportunity
看来只能抓准时机
and take him down with one powerful strike.
用强力的攻击一招干掉他了
Otherwise, we won't stand a chance.
不然感觉没有胜算
Taunt!
挑衅！
It's futile.
没用的
I've accumulated 20,000 damage so far.
目前累积的伤害是两万点
Let's settle this with this move!
就用这招一决胜负
Life Conversion!
生命转换！
Luna! Samimina!
露娜、萨米弥娜
-Get them to Nin! -Got it.
-把她们带去妮恩那边 -是
No way!
不会吧！
Lilia and Lily are incapacitated.
我们这边莉莉亚和莉莉都无法战斗了
What should we do?
该怎么办才好？
Even with my current mana enhancement,
现在的魔力强化程度
I'm still lacking in speed and strength.
在力量和速度方面都没有胜算
More…
要将更多…
I need to channel more mana into my body!
将更多的魔力注入全身！
Dang it!
可恶
That one hit depleted all of my shield force!
一击就把我的护盾耗尽了
But this means I can use Life Conversion one more time.
但是这样就能再用一次生命转换了
Let the mana flow throughout my body.
让魔力在全身流动
This time, I have to finish him with everything I've got!
这次一定要用尽所有力量干掉他
Life Conversion!
生命转换！
Rud!
路德！
Did my shield shatter?
护盾碎了吗？
Even with the mana enhancement,
就算注入魔力
it hurts so much I can't move.
也痛到无法动弹
Everyone, run!
大家快逃！
What happened?
发生什么事了？
Miss Luna! Miss Nin!
-露娜小姐、妮恩小姐 快到我身后 -我…
Samimina!
萨米弥娜！
-I have to hurry… -Dang it!
-得快点… -可恶！
I have to save everyone!
得快点去救大家才行！
Dang… Dang it!
可恶
I can't muster up my mana…
没办法顺利使出魔力
Come on!
快点！
Everyone's shield force…
大家的护盾…
is depleted!
都耗尽了
Luna!
露娜！
At this rate,
这样下去露娜…
Luna and everyone will…
以及大家都会…
Get up!
快动起来啊！
Please!
拜托了！
Curses!
可恶！
Let all my mana
让所有魔力全部流入身体里
Ignore the pain.
别管身上那些疼痛了
Break the limits!
突破自己的极限吧
I am…
因为我是…
the tank of this party!
这个队伍的肉盾！
Rud?
路德？
Destroy!
破坏掉吧
-There's a voice echoing in my head. -Destroy!
-脑中一直有个声音 -破坏掉吧
Destroy!
破坏掉吧
-It wants me to destroy everything. -Destroy…
-要我把一切破坏殆尽 -破坏掉吧
Channel more mana into my body.
让更多魔力在全身流动
Keep hitting until this guy breaks!
要一直打到这家伙不能再战斗为止
Over and over!
一直打
Rud!
路德！
Who is it?
是谁？
I can't see them.
看不太清楚
Is there someone else here?
还有其他人在这里吗？
Then,
那么…
I must destroy them too.
得一并破坏掉才行
Come to your senses!
快清醒过来！
Nin?
妮恩？
I put some magic in that slap.
我稍微用魔法打了你
Well? Are you back to normal?
怎么样？清醒过来了吗？
Uh… yeah.
呃 嗯
I was consumed by my mana.
我刚才好像被魔力吞噬了
Is that why I lost control?
所以才会丧失自我吗？
Rud!
路德！
My mana is acting up again…
魔力又擅自…
Destroy…
破坏掉吧
You should learn to control it.
是要学会控制
Those who cannot control mana
没办法控制魔力的人
will become monsters.
就会变成魔物
That voice…
那个声音…
I've heard that voice somewhere before.
我之前好像也在哪里听过
That's…
原来那是…
my voice.
我的声音
If this continues,
再这样下去
I might turn into a monster and go berserk.
我可能会变成魔物 最终失控
Rud!
路德！
Deep breaths.
先深呼吸
I need to control my mana.
必须控制住魔力才行
Rud!
路德！
Thank you, Nin.
妮恩 谢谢你
Thanks to you,
多亏有你
I was able to keep my mana under control.
我才能顺利控制住魔力
Thank goodness.
太好了
Now's not the time to let myself be overwhelmed by my mana.
现在可不是被魔力吞噬的时候
I have to protect everyone.
我必须保护大家
Greed!
葛利德！
The town you wish to protect is no more!
你要守护的地方已经完蛋了
I'll make sure they, along with your party,
我要让他们和你们一起
are completely eradicated
一个不留地
from this world!
从这个世上排除！
Nin, I need your help.
妮恩 我想请你帮个忙
Keep casting healing magic on me.
接下来不断对我施展回复魔法
Don't stop for even a second.
一刻都不能停下
I want to bet everything on this strike.
我想将一切全都赌在这一击上
I know this request is reckless…
我知道这个请求很乱来
What are you saying at a time like this?
事到如今 你还在说什么啊？
I'm the healer of this party. Go ahead and do what you need to do!
我可是你这个队伍的补师喔
Will do.
好
Just hold on a little longer, everyone! Don't give up!
再撑一下就好 大家别放弃！
Life Burst!
生命爆发！
You're a hundred years too early to lay a hand on me!
想碰到我 你还早了一百年呢！
Here's a newly made sword.
这边有一把新做好的剑
Take it!
快点拿去
Please heal the ones over there first
请让那边的人优先治疗
and get more bandages.
多拿一些绷带过来
Greed,
葛利德
we owe all of this to you.
这都是多亏了你
Adventurers, Vigilante Corps,
冒险者
Homunculi, Marius, Amon,
那些人造人
as long as I'm in the same space with everyone, my skills can link them.
只要跟大家待在同个空间
Sacrificial Shield!
牺牲之盾！
My body suddenly became lighter.
身体好像突然变轻了耶
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
The shield force isn't decreasing anymore.
护盾不会减少了
Is this…
这该不会是…
Rud's skill?
路德的技能？
Greed.
葛利德
Thanks to you showing me the vision of Avancia,
多亏你让我看到阿凡锡亚的景象
I was able to transfer all the shield force damage from everyone
我才能把这个空间里 所有人的护盾损伤
in this space onto myself.
全部转移到自己身上
As the strongest tank,
身为最强肉盾的我…
I will protect…
一定会守住
everyone!
这一切的！
Life Conversion!
生命转换！
Big Brother?
哥哥？
Is that Rud?
是路德吗？
Have they returned?
他们回来了吗？
It's Rud!
是路德！
Rud!
路德！
Big Brother!
哥哥
Manicia!
玛妮西娅
Everyone!
各位
Big Brother!
哥哥！
I always believed
我一直相信你绝对会回来
I've always come back, haven't I?
我不是每次都回来了吗？
That's true.
说得也是呢
Welcome back, Big Brother!
欢迎回来 哥哥
I'm back, Manicia.
我回来了 玛妮西娅
Rud!
路德
Marius. Amon.
玛里乌斯、亚蒙
Is everyone all right?
你们都没事啊
There were just too many of them.
因为数量实在太多了
I couldn't hold all of them back like you did.
我没办法像你那样 顾到所有地方
But we managed to hold the fort.
但还是勉强把城镇守住了
Thank you.
谢谢你们两位
-Rud!
-路德！
You actually conquered the labyrinth in such a short time!
你真的在这么短的时间内 攻破迷宫啦？
Incredible!
太强了！
Everyone…
各位…
It's thanks to all of you for helping protect Avancia,
多亏有你们帮忙守护城镇
that we were able to successfully destroy the labyrinth.
我们才能成功破坏迷宫
Thank you, everyone.
谢谢大家
Mister Rud?
路德先生？
Rud really is
路德果然…
-the strongest tank!
-是最强肉盾！
I am Rud. I am a tank.
我 路德的职业是肉盾
This is the story of how I, a tank,
这是讲述身为队伍盾职的我
became a hero.
摇身一变成为主角
I will continue to work hard
今后也会为了守护一切
and protect everyone.
而努力奋斗的故事